<!--
 ! Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
 ! contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
 ! this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
 ! The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
 ! (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
 ! the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ! 
 !      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ! 
 ! Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 ! distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 ! WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
 ! See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 ! limitations under the License.
 !-->
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document> 
  <header> 
    <title>PDFBox - .NET Version</title> 
    <meta name="keywords">Java PDF Library, pdftotext, PDF to text, ..NET pdf text extraction, pdf ASP, pdf .NET</meta>
  </header> 
  <body> 
    <section>
        <title>.NET Version</title>
        <p>
            Even though PDFBox is written in Java, there is also a .NET version that is available.  It utilizes <a href="http://www.ikvm.net">IKVM</a>
            to create a fully functioning PDF library for the .NET framework.  The released version contains a bin directory with all of the
            required DLL files.  For the command line applications that are available in the Java version a native windows executable is
            also included.  This page contains information that is specific to using the .NET version of PDFBox.
        </p>
        <section>
          <title>log4j</title>
          <p>
          PDFBox no longer requires log4j!  Older versions used to require you to configure log4j before using it in .NET
          </p>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Lucene</title>
          <p>
          The way that IKVM works is that DLLs are only compatible when used with the dependent DLLs that are used to build them.  For example, in 
          order to build the PDFBox DLL, a lucene DLL needs to be built, then the PDFBox DLL.  The PDFBox DLL now depends on that <b>*exact*</b>
          lucene DLL.  This means that if you build your own version of the lucene DLL then you also need to rebuild the PDFBox DLL.  Your best bet
          is to use the lucene/pdfbox that is shipped with PDFBox.
          </p>
        </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
